Guide to the James E. Jackson Audiotapes Collection OH.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Lectures, Speeches, 1973-1994; 2.75 Linear Feet in 11 boxes
  - Party / Youth (8), Undated (Box 7, Cassette 224)
  - Paul Robeson Commemoration - New Zealand's Tribute, Aug 1976 (Box 7, Cassette 225)
  - Peace History of the Party's Position on African-American Equality, Undated (Box 7, Cassette 226)
  - Peace Workshop, Undated (Box 7, Cassette 227)
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (2), Undated (Box 7, Cassette 228)
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (3), Undated (Box 7, Cassette 229)
  - Side 1: Weinstock, L.: Trade Unione Movement, Bio - Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois; Side 2: Jackson, J.: Petty Burgeois Nationalism (1), Undated (Box 7, Cassette 230)
  - Petty Burgeois Nationalism (2), Undated (Box 7, Cassette 231)
  - Philosophy, Undated (Box 7, Cassette 232)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Undated (Box 7, Cassette 233)
  - Philosophy (2), Mar 1977 (Box 7, Cassette 234)
  - Philosophy (3), Mar 1977 (Box 7, Cassette 235)
  - Philosophy, Oct 1982 (Box 7, Cassette 236)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Materialism, Oct 1982 (Box 7, Cassette 237)
  - Philosophy / Dialectical MaterialismNational School, Mar 1977 (Box 7, Cassette 238)
  - Philosophy, Dialectics (4), Dec 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 239)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (2)AYD Reports, TM Report, Dec 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 240)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (3), Dec 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 241)
  - Political Economy, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 242)
  - Political Economy, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 243)
  - Political Economy (3-4), Undated (Box 8, Cassette 244)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Inflation, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 245)
  - Side 1: Political Economy / Inflation; Side 2: Socialism, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 246)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1974 (Box 8, Cassette 247)
  - Political Economy, Feb 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 248)
  - Political Economy, Commodity ProductionLecture and Afterword Session, Feb 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 249)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Accumulation of the Capital, Feb 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 250)
  - Side 1: Lumer, Hy: Monetary Crisis; Side 2: Jackson, James: Political Economy Review (2), Dec 1975 (Box 8, Cassette 251)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976 (Box 8, Cassette 252)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Questioning Students, Jan 1976 (Box 8, Cassette 253)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976 (Box 8, Cassette 254)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1976 (Box 8, Cassette 255)
  - Political Economy (1), Mar 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 256)
  - Political Economy (2), Mar 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 257)
  - Political Economy (3), Mar 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 258)
  - Political Economy, Questions on (3), Mar 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 259)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 260)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1978 (Box 8, Cassette 261)
  - Political Economy (final), Jul 1978 (Box 8, Cassette 262)
  - Politics and Revolution (2)National School, Mar 1977 (Box 8, Cassette 263)
  - Portland, Maine Radio, Oct 1986 (Box 8, Cassette 264)
  - Side 1: Principles of Party Organization and Functioning; Side 2: Industrial Concentration, Feb 1976 (Box 8, Cassette 265)
  - Q&A On Children; Soviet Prophet, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 266)
  - Questions and Report from GRPS, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 267)
  - Questions for James E. Jackson, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 268)
  - Racism (5-6?), Undated (Box 8, Cassette 269)
  - Side 1: Racism; Side 2: Cont'd + Q&A's, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 270)
  - Racism, Fight Against, Undated (Box 8, Cassette 271)
  - Side 1: Racism with Mike Welch; Side 2: Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974 (Box 8, Cassette 272)
  - Report back from Workshops (Jackson, J.; Meyers, G.), Undated (Box 9, Cassette 273)
  - Report on 60th Anniversary of Soviet Union, Dec 1977 (Box 9, Cassette 274)
  - Report on Trip to China, Jul 1988 (Box 9, Cassette 275)
  - Revolution Process / Components of Revolution, Aug 1977 (Box 9, Cassette 276)
  - Revolutionary Conditions, Jan 1976 (Box 9, Cassette 277)
  - School Evaluation (1), Feb 1976 (Box 9, Cassette 278)
  - School Evaluation (2), Feb 1976 (Box 9, Cassette 279)
  - School Graduation, Closing Speech, Mar 1975 (Box 9, Cassette 280)
  - Situation of Black Americans, May 1979 (Box 9, Cassette 281)
  - Social Economics 2/12, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 282)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Discussion and Reports 2/28, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 283)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Questions on Political Economy, Mar 1977 (Box 9, Cassette 284)
  - Socialism, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 285)
  - Side 1: Socialism; Side 2: Lenin, the Party, Style in Leadership, Mar 1973 (Box 9, Cassette 286)
  - On Socialism (3), May 1981 (Box 9, Cassette 287)
  - On Socialism (4), May 1981 (Box 9, Cassette 288)
  - Socialism and Communism (1), Undated (Box 9, Cassette 289)
  - Socialism and the Soviet Union, Aug 1979 (Box 9, Cassette 290)
  - Socialist Convention / Unemployment (4), May 1979 (Box 9, Cassette 291)
  - Socialist Revolution, Aug 1977 (Box 9, Cassette 292)
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (1), Undated; cuid13966 (Box 9, Cassette 293, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid13966)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 60 min.
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (2), Undated; cuid13967 (Box 9, Cassette 294, Box Digitized Access Files, E-records cuid13967)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 62 min.
  - Soviet Union, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 295)
  - Soviet Union, Aug 1974 (Box 9, Cassette 296)
  - Soviet Union, Jul 1981 (Box 9, Cassette 297)
  - On the Soviet Union Berlin Conference, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 298)
  - Staff Seminar Discussion, May 1979 (Box 9, Cassette 299)
  - Side 1: The State; Side 2: Q&A, Undated (Box 9, Cassette 300)
  - The State, Feb 1975 (Box 9, Cassette 301)
  - The State, Feb 1975 (Box 9, Cassette 302)
  - Steel Strikes (?) and Socialism, Jul 1977 (Box 10, Cassette 303)
  - Side 1: Strategy; Side 2: United Front, Tactics, Sectarianism with M. Welch, S. Douglas, Aug 1974 (Box 10, Cassette 304)
  - Strategy and Tactics (2), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 305)
  - Side 1: Strategy and Tactics; Side 2: Irish Struggles, Mar 1977 (Box 10, Cassette 306)
  - Strategy and Tactics, Aug 1977 (Box 10, Cassette 307)
  - Strategy and Tactics with Gus Hall, Apr 1988 (Box 10, Cassette 308)
  - Side 1: On Strategy and Tactics / Introduction of L. Dlugan; Side 2: Dlugan, Lee: Monopoly Prices and Profits, Imperialism / Historical, Jan 1976 (Box 10, Cassette 309)
  - Suslov, In Memorial To, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 310)
  - Side 1: Theory of Knowledge; Side 2: Blank, Jan 1976 (Box 10, Cassette 311)
  - Trade Union, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 312)
  - Side 1: Trade Union (White; Jackson, J.); Side 2: Woman Question(White; Jackson, J.), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 313)
  - Side 1: Trade Union; Side 2: National Question, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 314)
  - Trade Union Meeting or Conference, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 315)
  - Transition to Social Revolution and Left Center, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 316)
  - Trotsky, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 317)
  - Trotskyism, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 318)
  - United Front, Undated (Box 10, Cassette 319)
  - United Front (2-3), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 320)
  - United Front (3-4), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 321)
  - Side 1: United Front; Side 2: The YWLL (Young Workers' Liberation League), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 322)
  - Urgent Tasks in Fight for PeaceCentral Committee Report, Nov 1979 (Box 10, Cassette 323)
  - VALB Socialist Scholars ConferenceWorkshop includes: Wellman, Saul, Apr 1994 (Box 10, Cassette 324)
  - Washington, Feb 1980 (Box 10, Cassette 325)
  - WBA I - J. Jackson with Bogdan Denitsch, Jan 1982 (Box 10, Cassette 326)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Memorial Lecture, Boston, Mar 1989 (Box 10, Cassette 327)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois: Our Black Titan, Washington, D.C., Feb 1973 (Box 10, Cassette 328)
  - West Berlin, Jan 1984 (Box 10, Cassette 329)
  - Women's Equality (3-4), Undated (Box 10, Cassette 330)
  - Women's Question, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 331)
  - Women's Question (1) with J. Teixeira, Aug 1977 (Box 11, Cassette 332)
  - Women's Question (2), Aug 1977 (Box 11, Cassette 333)
  - Women's Question (3), Aug 1977 (Box 11, Cassette 334)
  - Working Class History of the Nationalities Wheel (?)22nd Convention, Aug 1979 (Box 11, Cassette 335)
  - World Peace CouncilMedal Ceremony for J. Jackson, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 336)
- Series III: Speeches by Others, 1968-1990, undated; 0.5 Linear Feet in 2 boxes
  This series consists of audio recordings of lectures given by people other than Jackson, on topics relating to the Communist Party USA (CPUSA), communism, labor unions, and international issues. Speakers include Gus Hall and Henry Winston. Material dates from 1968 to 1990, with some items undated.
  - Bert, Erik: Communist International, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 337)
  - Brodine, M. J.: Asians in America, Feb 1977 (Box 11, Cassette 338)
  - Chandra, Romesh: World Peace Council, Jan 1978 (Box 11, Cassette 339)
  - Dennis, Ellen with O. Harrington, P. Miriam: Berlin, Nov 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 340)
  - Diskin, Louis and Others, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 341)
  - Fitzgerald, Albert: About Himself and about the Unions, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 342)
  - Hall, Gus: Side 1: PA Political Union; Side 2: Boston Conference, Nov 1981 (Box 11, Cassette 343)
  - Hall, Gus: Main Address, N.C., Jan 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 344)
  - Hall, Gus: On Greece + Q&A's, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 345)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Aug 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 346)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Nov 1988 (Box 11, Cassette 347)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Jan 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 348)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Feb 1989 (Box 11, Cassette 349)
  - Side 1: Hall, Gus Update; Side 2: J. Jackson, Jul 1990 (Box 11, Cassette 350)
  - Hudson, Hosea, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 351)
  - Lipschutz, Joan; Jacques, Jeff, Aug 1977 (Box 11, Cassette 352)
  - Mobhito, Moses: General Secretary, C.P. South Africa, Mar 28, 1968 (?) (Box 11, Cassette 353)
  - Mobhito, Moses; Mullens, Leith; Diskin, Louis, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 354)
  - Side 1: Mora, Grace; Side 2: Winston, Henry, Skit of Students, Mar 1975 (Box 11, Cassette 355)
  - Patrinos, Sandy: Strategy and Tactics: Party School, Mar 1975 (Box 11, Cassette 356)
  - Shelby: Female Conflicts, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 357)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (2), Mar 1975 (Box 11, Cassette 358)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (3), Mar 1975 (Box 11, Cassette 359)
  - Side 1: Storey, Rasheed / Afternoon Plenary; Side 2: Afternoon Plenary, Undated (Box 11, Cassette 360)
  - Tyner, Jarvis: Political Report, Mar 1987 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 361)
  - Winston, Henry: Communist Party, Dec 1975 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 362)
  - Winston, Henry: School Opening, Feb 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 363)
  - Winston, Henry Speech (3), Mar 1975 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 364)
  - Winston, Henry: Party Theory (3), Party School, Mar 1975 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 365)
  - Unknown Speaker (man): Class Struggle, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 366)
  - Unknown Speaker (man)Communist Unity, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 367)
  - Unknown Speaker(s): Discussion on an event at Carnegie Hall, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 368)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Labor Union and the Party, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 369)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Martin Luther King, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 370)
  - Unknown speakers: Political Economy - Student Session, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 371)
  - Unknown speakers: Students' Discussions and Presentations on Capitalism, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 372)
- Series IV: 7 inch reel of 1/4 inch-wide Recording Tapes, 1965; 0.25 Linear Feet in 1 box
  This series consists of audio recordings of Kofi Patsu and unidentified speakers at the Young Farmers Rally at Kumasi Chance in Ghana in 1965.
  - Patsu, Kofi and other unknown speakers: Young Farmers Rally at Kumasi Chance, Mar 1965 (Box Shared Tamiment 089, Cassette 373)